Oleksandr Ratushnyi

Senior front-end engineer

Kremenchuk, Ukraine T: +380679340776 E: <u>alexander.ratushnyi@gmail.com</u>
G: https://github.com/a1exalexander

L: <u>alexander-ratushnyi</u>

W: https://sashkoratushnyi.com

Summary

A skilled Front-end Developer from Ukraine with over 6 years of experience, my main stack is React + TypeScript. I am also experienced in Node.js development, so I'm actually a full-stack, but at heart I'm a front-end. Specialized in full-stack javascript development, development discovery, web architecture team management, development processes, and development delivery. I have successfully developed and managed over 22 projects from inception to production, with more than 15 handled independently. Additionally, I have experience in teaching and creating courses in front-end development.

Technologies

Javascript, HTML, CSS, TypeScript, React, Next.js, Remix, Vue, Nuxt, Node.js, NestJS, Fastify, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Prisma, Redis, Redux, MobX, MVC, DDD, CA, FSD, OOP, SDLC

Professional Experience

Merge

(2018 - Present) Full-stack Developer / CTO / Co-founder

Engaged in the development of web applications primarily in the fintech and SaaS sectors.

Responsibilities included managing in-house developers, setting up the company's processes, hiring, and mentoring of developers. Key projects involved developing innovative financial technology solutions and scalable SaaS platforms.

Merge Academy

(2022 - 2023) Course Author / Teacher

I created a front-end development course program and started teaching it, developed a website for the academy and helped with setting up automation of course processes.

WiseAlpha

(2020) Front-end Developer

Trading and Technology for the Corporate Bond Market. Developed new features on the old and good Backbone.

Beetroot Academy

(2019 - 2021) Teacher

Taught a course on front-end development and successfully released two groups of students.

Freelance

(2018 - 2021) Front-end Developer

Part-time freelance role involving diverse projects, showcasing adaptability and skill in various front-end technologies.

Education

(2014) Kharkiv National University of Internal Affairs - Hold a Bachelor's Degree in Jurisprudence (2017) Graduated from the National Academy of Internal Affairs. Hold a Master's Degree in Jurisprudence

Languages: English (Upper-intermediate), Ukrainian (Native)

Hobbies: Photography, photo retouching, riding a bicycle, pizza cooking

Portfolio: https://sashkoratushnyi.com